=== DOCX File: SPC STANDBY_SOP_V1.8_2025.05.27.docx ===

Paragraph 10: To be included in 5.1.2.01 & 9.1.1.01
Paragraph 11: OPUS SPC/BKG "Standby" Function
Paragraph 26: CAUTION!
If you are holding a hard copy of this document, beware that it is maintained on a cloud based solution and that it may not be the latest version. 
Hard copies are not encouraged to use.
Paragraph 28: Version Control
Paragraph 31: Contact Information
Paragraph 32: Table of Contents
Paragraph 34: 1. Process
Paragraph 35: 1.1 Process Description
Paragraph 36: When Booking Staff creates a booking, the system will automatically check for c. If there are any issues with the booking related to Overall Trunk/ POL/ Feeder/ Customer allocation, EQ or commodity restrictions, the booking will become 窶牢tandby窶・booking and will be then handled by the Standby Booking process. If there is no restriction/ constraint, BKG staff (Off/ On Shore) can confirm and release booking instantly.
Paragraph 38: 1.2 Process Flow
Paragraph 40: When On/ Offshore booking staff creates a booking, the system will check for any restrictions/ constraints that were set up by GHQ/ RHQ trade teams. If there are no restrictions/ constraints, the booking will become firm instantly. If there are any restrictions/ constraints related to allocation/ EQ/ commodity, the booking will be escalated to the respective party to review and make a decision.
Paragraph 43: 1.3 Roles
Paragraph 44: There are Three Tiers of business roles. Tier 1 is the On/ Off-shore CSVC manager, Tier 2 the On-Shore CSVC manager and approvers, and Tier 3 GHQ/RHQ Space Controllers.
Paragraph 45: In the booking escalation process, the booking will be escalated to Tier 2- On-Shore CSVC Manager and approvers. Tier 2 will guide back to Tier 1, and Tier 1 will then be able to Firm or Cancel the booking. Please refer to the Booking Office Tier and Role table.
Paragraph 46: Booking Office Tier and Role
Paragraph 48: 1.3.1  Roles Explanation
Paragraph 49: Standby Booking Roles can be set up by GHQ/RHQ/BKG office User IDs in Booking/Documentation- Standby Booking Role Setup. For instance, in EA/SA, there are Three Tiers of roles, each Tier represents different type of User IDs, from On/Offshore Booking Staff to GHQ/RHQ Space Controllers.
Paragraph 50: (Service mgmt->booking/documentation->setup->standby booking role setup)
Paragraph 52: 1.4 Process Steps
Paragraph 53: 1.4.1 Space Control 窶・Data Setup
Paragraph 54: 1.4.1.1 Standby Guidance Setup
Paragraph 56: Standby Guidance Setup
Paragraph 57: 1.4.1.2 Standby Priority Setup Creation
Paragraph 58: The setting of Priority rule is crucial, different ways of setting will result in different Final Guidance. SINHQ窶冱 Priority rule setup is standardised and applied to all Trades, including both HKGHQ and SINHQ. Asterisk (*) stands for all possible Guides (example GD1-GD6 and GDN).
Paragraph 59: Each region (example RICHQ, SAOHQ, LONHQ) also has their own set of Priority Set-ups depending on their business requirements.
Paragraph 62: Priority rule 1: If EQ Restriction is GD1, Final guidance will be GD1.
Paragraph 63: Priority rule 2: If EQ Restriction is GD6, Final guidance will be GD6.
Paragraph 64: Priority rule 3: If EQ Restriction is GD4, Final guidance will be GD4.
Paragraph 65: >Deleted as SINHQ will use Sequential Logic that covers Rule 3
Paragraph 66: Priority rule 4 & 5: If EQ Availability Master is GDN/GD1, Final guidance will be GD1.
Paragraph 67: Priority rule 6 & 7: If EQ Availability Master is GD6/GD4, Final guidance will be GD6/GD4 respectively.
Paragraph 68: Priority rule 8: If VIP is GD1, Final guidance will be GD1.
Paragraph 69: Priority rule 9: If Loading/POL Customer is GDN, Final guidance will be GD1.
Paragraph 70: Priority rule 10: If Trunk Customer is GDN, Final guidance will be GD1.
Paragraph 71: >Loading/POL Master = Trunk-Loading Tab Constraint
Paragraph 72: >Loading/POL Customer = Customer Tab Constraint with Loading Port/POL set-ups
Paragraph 73: >Trunk Master = Trunk-Overall Tab Constraint
Paragraph 74: >Trunk Customer = Customer Tab Constraint with VVD allocation set-ups
Paragraph 75: >Feeder Master = Feeder Tab Constraint
Paragraph 76: >Feeder Customer = Customer Tab Constraint with Transhipment set-ups
Paragraph 79: 1.4.1.3 Sequential Validation
Paragraph 80: Sequential Validation checks Master Constraint Table Tabs like a decision-tree flow chart. Instead of checking all constraints simultaneously and using the Priority Rule Table to determine final guidance, Sequential Validation checks a Constraint Tab before moving on to the next Tab, thus allowing multiple constraints to be considered for a final guidance.
Paragraph 81: Commodity Restriction will be checked first, followed by EQ restriction, then EQ availability, and finally for Trunk-loading, Feeder and Trunk-overall (Master Tab and Customer Tab).
Paragraph 82: Sequential Validation can be activated or deactivated in the Standby Priority Setup Creation screen.
Paragraph 84: When activated, Standby Priority Set-up Creation Table (1.4.1.2), Sequential Validation Logic (1.4.1.3) and Trade Teams窶・set-up in Master Constraint Table (1.4.1.6) work together to derive the Final Guidance for a booking. If deactivated, Final Guidance will be derived by Standby Priority Set-up Creation Table (1.4.1.2) and Trade Teams窶・set-up in Master Constraint Table (1.4.1.6) only.
Paragraph 85: Currently SINHQ and RICHQ are using Sequential Validation as follows;
Paragraph 86: Sequential Validation Flowchart
Paragraph 89: 1.4.1.4 Standby Revalidation Logic
Paragraph 90: Bookings that have already gone through Standby and given guidance can be revalidated by the system based on the Hard Coding Setup Table. If Validation is 窶廸窶・ a change in the booking item (example POR) will not cause a revalidation. If Validation is 窶弸窶・ a change in the field (example DEL) will cause the booking to be revalidated.
Paragraph 91: However, revalidation will not work when the booking item is updated using the Group VVD/Port Assign UI.
Paragraph 98: (Service Management > Booking/Documentation > Setup > Hard Coding Setup)
Paragraph 101: 1.4.1.5 Booking Status Definition
Paragraph 102: In the Booking screen, there are Two boxes representing the status. The first box is the status of the booking itself, and the second box is the Standby status.
Paragraph 110: *F/blank in Asia means booking is not validated by Standby. In most cases, the user is not registered in the Standby Hardcoding table. In some cases, due to other system errors.
Paragraph 111: When a booking is Standby, the normal booking process is suppressed.
Paragraph 112: Trans Request Order on Booking Creation
Paragraph 113: FAX/EDI on Booking Creation (Booking Receipt Notice, Draft BL etc.)
Paragraph 114: Booking Receipt Notice (Fax/Email)
Paragraph 115: Booking Receipt Notice (EDI)
Paragraph 116: Booking EDI Transmit to Terminal
Paragraph 117: Empty Container Release Order
Paragraph 118: VGM Dashboard
Paragraph 119: 1.4.1.6 Master Constraint Table Creation
Paragraph 120: Master Constraint Table allows GHQ/RHQ trade teams to have an overall management of space allocation and constraints by Trunk-Overall, Trunk-Loading, Feeder, EQ, Commodity and Customer. GHQ/ RHQ Trade teams can update constraints and customer Account Plan in the Master Constraint Table.
Paragraph 122: Trunk-Overall
Paragraph 123: Trade Teams can set Trunk vessel窶冱 threshold % at trade level. For instance, FE2 WB Trunk vessel threshold is set as 85%, if actual booking volume is over 85%, GD4 will be triggered. Remarks will be shown in the standby popup detail page.
Paragraph 125: Trunk-Loading
Paragraph 126: Trade Teams can also set the Trunk-Loading threshold %. For instance, FE2 WB, Loading office NBOBB exceeds threshold % of 110%, GD4 will be triggered. Remarks will be shown in the standby popup detail page. Allocation also can be set by port pairs with TEU allocation and threshold %.
Paragraph 128: Customer (with <>7 or 10 days logic) in Asia
Paragraph 129: Customer Account Plan can be downloaded and uploaded from and into the system by Trade Teams in the Master Constraint Table. Guidance will be triggered when actual booking volume is above customer allocation.
Paragraph 131: There is also a 10-day logic in Master Constraint Table, the Final Guidance can be different when the booking is created more than 10 days before the first VVD窶冱 ETA, and less than 10 days before the first VVD窶冱 ETA (Count by hour: 1st VVD ETA - 10*24 hours).
Paragraph 132: For example, if the below booking is created more than 10 days before the first VVD窶冱 ETA, the booking will be GD1. However, if it is created less than 10days before the first VVD窶冱 ETA, booking will become GD4.
Paragraph 134: Customer GD4 Hard coding for Asia
Paragraph 135: Customer without allocation.
Paragraph 136: S/C or RFA info is not available in the Master Constraint Table.
Paragraph 137: Only apply to OCN bookings.
Paragraph 138: Weight Allocation
Paragraph 139: Set-up can be done via TEU or Total WGT allocation. Additional Average WGT MT/TEU per booking is also available under the Customer tab. Trades are also able to indicate if the WGT allocation is inclusive of tare weight by checking the 窶廣dd Tare Weight窶・box.
Paragraph 140: Tare weight is derived from OPUS Master Data for the specific container Type Size.
Paragraph 142: Common constraint
Paragraph 143: General comments/ guidance will be shown. However, the common guidance will not affect the Final Guidance.
Paragraph 144: Validation Error Pop-out Table
Paragraph 145: When users upload constraints using the "Upload Excel '' button, a validation error table will pop-out and identify the fields and possible reasons for errors. Line numbers in the Validation Error Table correspond to the Row numbers in Excel file. Excel file will have to be cleared of the errors, and reuploaded before the constraints can be saved in the Master Constraint Table.
Paragraph 151: Exact Match checkbox in EQ Restriction, EQ Availability & Customer Tabs
Paragraph 152: Exact Match checkbox allows users to specify whether a particular constraint is strictly applicable for a certain container type/size only and would not allow the release of any mixed bookings.
Paragraph 153: For example, a constraint with RF flag and Exact Match flag checked will not allow the release of mixed booking of 1xR5 and 10xD4.
Paragraph 155: Move Count Field in Trunk-Loading, EQ Restriction & Customer Tabs
Paragraph 156: This field gives users the option to control the move counts by indicating the limit under the 窶廴ove Count窶・field. The move count logic is also based on the total number of containers, not by total teu.
Paragraph 157: For example, a booking with 2xD4 is equal to 2 move counts. And if a constraint is created with a limit of 5 move counts, the booking will be guided as GDN as it is within the limit.
Paragraph 159: % Threshold in Customer Tab
Paragraph 160: The % threshold allows Trades to control the % of excess AP to release without changing the initial Account Plan numbers in case of high shortfall situations.
Paragraph 161: For example, allocation is 50 teus and % threshold is 200. The total bookings that can be released under this constraint will be 100 teus.
Paragraph 165: Code Field in Feeder Tab
Paragraph 166: This field allows users to input or select 窶弃RE窶・to set Pre-feeder constraints or 窶弃OST窶・for Post-feeder constraints in Feeder tab.
Paragraph 167: The final guide will be based on a Priority approach: GD6> GD2> GD3> GD5> GD4> GD1/ GDN.
Paragraph 168: If 窶弃RE/ POST窶・field is left blank, it will depend on Opus logic to decide if it is a PRE or POST Feeder.
Paragraph 170: Utilization Calculation Pop-Out in Master Constraint Table
Paragraph 171: This function allows users to check the constraints utilization which help users give updated directions or adjust the constraints if necessary. The 窶弑tilization窶・button is available on all tabs except for Commodity, Common and VIP tabs, and for this button to appear, the 窶彜elect窶・button must be clicked first.
Paragraph 173: E.g. Utilization calculation pop-out generated 14 teus for SEQ 8998908 as it captured below bookings. Utilization/ BKG VOL will be calculated automatically when VVD is available. If it is not, Sales/ EQ Week must be inputted in the pop-out to trigger the calculation.
Paragraph 180: Soft Warning Pop-Out in Master Constraint Table
Paragraph 181: The soft warning pop-out will appear when users create constraints with blank Trade/ T.Lane/ Transshipment Lane and when each line is registered in MCT directly (there is no validation for excel upload). And since this is only a soft warning, users can still save the constraint if they click OK to proceed.
Paragraph 183: Improve Master Constraint Table Performance with Backend Archiving Logic
Paragraph 184: There were some performance issues in the MCT UI as all non-deleted constraints were kept in the Standby Live Database even though they were not being used for current standby calculation, as VVDs have long sailed. So, in order to improve its performance, a backend Archive flag or logic was added so that the past data can be moved to the Standby History database via a weekly batch.
Paragraph 185: The criteria for the weekly archive data batch are as follows:
Paragraph 186: Customer Tab
Paragraph 187: Only for constraints with 1 VVD input
Paragraph 188: Based on last update date 4 months from current (only archive 4 months after a constraint窶冱 last update date)
Paragraph 189: Include BKG via WEQ, OTHERS and Blank
Paragraph 190: EQ Availability Tab
Paragraph 191: Only for constraints with EQ Date/ Full Cut Off To
Paragraph 192: Only archive if 窶廢Q Date/ Full Cut Off To窶・has passed during weekly archive batch
Paragraph 193: Standby judgement/ validation will refer to Standby Live Database only.
Paragraph 194: E.g. Retrieved 840 Archived constraints under FE2 service for 202347 and all the constraints have 1 VVD input and were updated more than 4 months ago.
Paragraph 198: Update in Standby Logic for SINHQ/HKGHQ/DXBHQ
Paragraph 199: Previously, standby judgement considered all Firm and Waiting bookings which resulted in bookings going to GD4, even though there may be no firm bookings or limited number of firm bookings compared to the allocation.
Paragraph 200: So, the Standby logic has been updated wherein it will only consider the total of self booking plus;
Paragraph 201: Firmed Booking Status
Paragraph 202: GD1 bookings that are not firmed yet (status W/F) due to further checking required for OOG/DG or other hold status by offshore/ onshore etc.
Paragraph 203: Other Standby Guide (e.g GD2/GD3/GD4/GD5) bookings that are currently in Waiting/ Standby status (W/S) or W/Blank or W/E status, but already guided by onshore to Firm (only pending action to firm it)
Paragraph 204: E.g. Below bookings were created before the AP was set up so all bookings went to GD4
Paragraph 206: Once the AP (12 teus) was set up, user recalculated all the bookings at the same time. After recalculation, they received below final guidance.
Paragraph 207: If there are more than one booking selected for recalculation, system will guide them on first-come-first-serve basis depending on the booking creation time.
Paragraph 208: Booking SINE70452400 went to GD4 as set up allocation was already exceeded. While the next booking SINE70453500 went to GD1 as it is still within the balance space.
Paragraph 211: Below fields were also added in the Standby Booking Status Report
Paragraph 212: BKG for Standby Judgement TEU/Box / TONS
Paragraph 213: When  窶廚urrent TTL TEU Calculation窶・is clicked, below fields will appear
Paragraph 214: Current BKG for Standby Judgement TEU/Box / TONS
Paragraph 215: Current Standby Firm/ Guided Firm TEU/Box /Tons
Paragraph 216: Current Standby Wait TEU/Box / TONS
Paragraph 218: Spot/ Non-Spot AP Constraint in Customer Tab
Paragraph 219: Spot and Non-Spot AP constraints were added in MCT Customer tab, which allow users to exclude AP volumes from Spot volumes and allow booking release judgement to be totally separated between Spot and AP.
Paragraph 221: Spot will be used for creation of a spot allocation and will act as a 窶弃arent窶・sequence of Account Plan. While the Non-Spot AP will function in a similar way to 窶廚ustomer窶・ however it is the 窶廚hild窶・of the Spot constraint which means that it would not be possible to create a Non-Spot AP constraint without creating a Spot constraint first.
Paragraph 222: In total, there are now three types in Customer Tab (Customer, Spot, and Non-Spot AP) and the Judgement Priority is Customer > Spot/Non-Spot AP. However, it is suggested to only use either the Customer Constraint OR Spot/Non-Spot AP constraints to avoid getting the wrong result.
Paragraph 224: E.g  Below constraints were created in Customer Tab.
Paragraph 226: Booking SINE05512600 referred to SEQ 7306068 as the RFA No. match.
Paragraph 234: While booking SINE05514800 referred to SEQ 7306067 as RFA No. NBON00621A is not a part of Non-Spot AP constraint. Non-Spot AP volume was also excluded from the Spot volume.
Paragraph 238: 1.4.1.7 Creation of Group RFAs
Paragraph 239: Multiple SC/RFAs can be grouped into a single GRFA. Allocation set for GRFA will be shared by the single SC/RFAs within the group. The grouping setup is to be done by Trade.
Paragraph 242: 1.4.1.8 Standby Hardcoding Table for Pre/Post Feeder
Paragraph 243: OPUS Standby judgement logic for Feeder Tab constraint is based on the Dominant or Non-Dominant leg. For a Dominant leg, Feeder logic is based on the pre feeder. While for a Non-Dominant leg, Feeder logic is based on the post feeder. The set-up in Feeder Tab must match OPUS Standby窶冱 logic or the constraint will not work to control the Feeder bookings.
Paragraph 244: However, it is possible to change the Standby Feeder logic on a GHQ/RHQ, Trade or Lane basis, using the Hard Coding Setup Table.
Paragraph 247: 1.4.2 Booking/ Documentation
Paragraph 248: 1.4.2.1 Standby Booking Status Report
Paragraph 249: Standby Booking Status Report gives everyone a fast view for the Final Guidance advised and other data to assist in determining if the booking is approved or declined.
Paragraph 251: All the standby bookings can be retrieved in the Standby Booking Status Report, with Standby reason, current Tier/Role and Direction given. Tier 2 and Tier 3 users will be able to send their guidance (Firm/Cancel/Direction/Firm as Rollpool/Comment) to BKG staff when the booking is being escalated to their Tier/Role, BKG staff are then able to confirm or cancel the booking.
Paragraph 253: In the Standby Booking Status Report, CM/Teu and Ave CM/Teu information are also available for bookings assigned with Standby Status: S, X or E. This is designed to help users in their decision-making during booking release.
Paragraph 254: CM/Teu (EPP-A or B) = [Ocean Freight (OFT) + Surcharge (SUR) 窶・Cost (EPP-A or B)]/Total Teu
Paragraph 255: However, around 40-50% of the bookings have 窶廸o Rate窶・in the CM/Teu calculation due to no applicable rate for the contract, or no applicable rate for the container type size of the contract when the booking was created.
Paragraph 256: For such cases, Users can refer to the Ave CM/Teu (EPP-A or B) instead. Calculation of Ave CM/TEU is based on bookings with application dates of 3 months before the PF First POL ETD date. And considers Service Scope, Revenue Lane and SC/RFA number. For example, when Standby was validated, the PF First POL ETD is on 21/Mar/2021. Then the Ave CM/TEU will be calculated based on bookings with Application dates from 20/Dec/2020 to 20/Mar/2021.
Paragraph 257: Detailed information regarding CM/Teu and Ave CM/Teu calculation logic in Standby Booking Status Report can be found in this guide.
Paragraph 260: 1.4.2.2 Standby Booking Monitoring Report
Paragraph 261: In the Standby Booking Monitoring Report, total booking volume can be retrieved by Trade/ Dominant leg/Bound/ VVD, including all Firm/ Waiting/Standby/ Error bookings.
Paragraph 267: 2. Business Rules
Paragraph 268: 2.1 Standby Priority & Guidance Setup 窶・Business Rule Interpretation
Paragraph 269: Please refer to 1.4 Process Steps
Paragraph 270: 2.2 Final Guidance, Escalation, Decision Making Authority
Paragraph 271: 2.2.1 Country with Off-shore Booking Team
Paragraph 272: Please refer to 1.4.1.1 Standby Guidance Setup
Paragraph 273: 2.2.2 Country without Off-shore Booking Team
Paragraph 274: Please refer to 1.4.1.1 Standby Guidance Setup
Paragraph 275: 2.2.3 Trade-specific booking release process
Paragraph 276: 2.2.3.1 AET
Paragraph 279: Within the Account Plan, can release instantly.
Paragraph 280: For Green customers, give discretion to release up to 120%(*) of AP
Paragraph 281: For Non-Green customers, need to wait till 1
Paragraph 282: 0 day cut off for beyond-AP portion.
Paragraph 283: * varies by trade direction
Paragraph 286: Passing 10 day cut-off, release all Green "standby" booking accumulated so far.
Paragraph 287: For Green customers, if sales forecast(**) tells it's coming later, need to reserve space till last minutes
Paragraph 288: If there are still remaining space, can start release Non-Green customer "Standby" bookings
Paragraph 289: ** Sales forecast is very important to protect Green customer space after 10 days.
Paragraph 294: 3. ONE Quote Standby Functions
Paragraph 295: 3.1 ONE Quote Allocation Set-up
Paragraph 296: 3.1.1 BKG VIA field
Paragraph 297: Under the Customer tab, trades can set allocations for ONE Quote bookings through the 窶廝KG VIA窶・column by selecting 窶弩EQ窶・
Paragraph 302: 3.1.1.2 BKG VIA filter
Paragraph 303: For easy access, trades are also able to utilise the 窶廝KG VIA窶・filter to check WEQ constraints in the Master Constraint Table.
Paragraph 307: 3.1.2 POR/POL/POD/DEL Allocation
Paragraph 308: ONE Quote allocations can also be set by POR/POL/POD/DEL.
Paragraph 314: 3.1.3 ONE Quote Standby Guidance and VVD removal from Platform
Paragraph 315: If total bookings exceed the allocations set under 3.1.1 and 3.1.2, bookings exceeding the threshold will go into GD6 for rejection should trade set-up specific allocations as GD6.
Paragraph 316: VVDs will also be removed from ONE Quote platform (closed) if total bookings exceed allocations at the time of judgement.
Paragraph 317: Scenario 1
Paragraph 318: If WEQ allocations are set as GD6.
Paragraph 320: Scenario 2
Paragraph 321: If WEQ allocations are set as GD6.
Paragraph 323: 3.1.4 Premium Flag Field
Paragraph 324: Premium flag allocation can be set under the premium flag field.
Paragraph 325: Scenario 1
Paragraph 326: Total WEQ allocation for all customers (with and without premium flag) at 200teus.
Paragraph 327: Bookings will go to GD6 once hit the threshold above 200teus
Paragraph 329: Scenario 2
Paragraph 330: Total WEQ allocation non-premium customers at 50teus.
Paragraph 331: Total WEQ allocation for all customers (with and without premium flag) at 200teus.
Paragraph 332: If total bookings for non-premium customers is only at 15teus, premium customers can load up to 185teus.
Paragraph 335: Scenario 3
Paragraph 336: Total WEQ allocation premium customers at 50teus.
Paragraph 337: Total WEQ allocation for all customers (with and without premium flag) at 100teus.
Paragraph 338: Premium customers can load up to 50teus before hitting the threshold for escalation.
Paragraph 339: Should there be nil premium bookings, maximum for non-premium customers would be up to 100teus.
Paragraph 342: Scenario 4
Paragraph 343: For cases where only premium cargo is offered in ONE Quote, the set-up as per Scenario 1 will be sufficient. I.e. Premium flag 窶彙lank窶・in Standby.
Paragraph 344: Detailed information regarding ONE Quote Standby Set-Up can be found in this guide.
Paragraph 361: 4. Supporting Information
Paragraph 362: 4.1 System Manuals
Paragraph 363: Notes by CLT
Paragraph 364: How to Guide by NA
Paragraph 365: ONE Quote Standby Set-up Guideline
Paragraph 366: 4.2 Additional Documents
Paragraph 367: 4.2.1 Test Scenario (Asia)
Paragraph 368: 4.2.1.1 Scenario 1: Trunk Overall
Paragraph 370: 4.2.1.2 Scenario 2: Trunk Loading
Paragraph 372: 4.2.1.3 Scenario 3: Customer
Paragraph 374: 4.2.1.4 Scenario 4: Common
Paragraph 377: 4.2.1.5 Scenario 5: 10 Days Logic
Paragraph 378: Below sample booking has the creation date less than 10 days to the first VVD窶冱 ETA, therefore, even though Trunk-Overall, Trunk-Loading, and Customer are all within allocation, due to the setup of 10 days function, Final Guidance will still become GD4 (Escalate to CSVC Manager).
Paragraph 382: 4.2.2 Launch Status 窶・Countries and Trades
Paragraph 383: Refer to Standby New Matrix.
Paragraph 385: 4.2.3 Asia Booking Process
Paragraph 386: Booking Acceptance Priority Rules under Standby Function
Paragraph 391: 4.2.3.1 Split/ Combine/ NROF bookings
Paragraph 392: Booking Split
Paragraph 393: In case of booking split, if the original booking is already Firm or blank, standby logic will not be running. However, if the original booking is standby status, standby logic will be running when booking is split.
Paragraph 394: Booking Combine
Paragraph 395: In the case of Booking combine, if the booking status of all original bookings are Firm or Blank, standby logic is no longer required because it's already firmed. However, if one of the original bookings or all original bookings are standby status, standby logic will be running
Paragraph 397: No Rates on File (NROF) bookings
Paragraph 398: For NROF bookings, final guidance will become GD4, and escalate to relative parties.
Paragraph 399: Empty bookings
Paragraph 400: Empty bookings are not in current Standby Booking scope.
Paragraph 402: 4.2.3.2 Customer over account plan
Paragraph 405: 4.2.3.3 Releasing of GD1 bookings/ Offline checking of Blacklist
Paragraph 406: At the current stage, GD1 bookings are not released automatically. The bookings are to be manually held and some other constraints/ restrictions are required to be checked offline and manually by offshore booking staff on all GD1 bookings before releasing.
Paragraph 410: 4.3 Glossary
Paragraph 411: Glossary for OPUS Container

--- Table 1 ---
Row 1: Ver | Date 
(DD.MM.YYYY) | BP Author (Office/Region) | Revision Notes
Row 2: 1.0 | 26.03.2019 | Jessie Wang (GHQ SYM BI)
Row 3: 1.1 | 20.11.2019 | Jessie Wang (GHQ SYM BI) | Added G.RFA in 1.4.1.2
Row 4: 1.2 | 11.10.2021 | Wan Yan Sia (GHQ DYM BPM) | Updated Roles in 1.3
Added Creation of G.RFA in 1.4.1.3
Added ONE Quote Standby Functions in 3
Updated Launch Status 窶・Countries and Trades in 4.2.2
Row 5: 1.3 | 24.03.2022 | Wan Yan Sia (GHQ DYM BPM) | Updated Standby Priority Set-up Creation in 1.4.1.2
Added Sequential Validation in 1.4.1.3
Added Standby Revalidation Logic in 1.4.1.4
Updated Booking Status Definition in 1.4.1.5
Updated Master Constraint Table Creation in 1.4.1.6
Updated Weight Allocation and Added Validation Error Pop-out Table in 1.4.1.6
Updated Creation of Group RFAs in 1.4.1.7
Added Standby Hardcoding Table for Pre/Post Feeder in 1.4.1.8
Updated Standby Booking Role Setup in 1.4.2.1
Added link to ONE Quote Standby Set-up Guideline in 4.1
Row 6: 1.4 | 29.12.2022 | Wan Yan Sia (GHQ DYM BPM) | Removed Standby Booking Role Setup in 1.4.2.1
Updated Standby Booking Status Report in 1.4.2.1
Updated Premium Flag Field in 3.1.4
Row 7: 1.5 | 08.05.2023 | Pamela Sevilla (GHQ DYM BPM) | Added Exact Match Checkbox in 1.4.1.6
Added Move Count Field  in 1.4.1.6
Row 8: 1.6 | 07.12.2023 | Pamela Sevilla (GHQ DYM BPM) | Added % Threshold in 1.4.1.6
Added Code Field in 1.4.1.6
Row 9: 1.7 | 18.11.2024 | Pamela Sevilla (GHQ DYM BPM) | Added Utilization Calculation Pop-out in 1.4.1.6
Added Soft Warning Pop-out in 1.4.1.6
Added Backend Archiving Logic in 1.4.1.6
Row 10: 1.8 | 27.05.2025 | Pamela Sevilla (GHQ DYM BPM) | Added Update in Standby Judgement Logic in 1.4.1.6
Added Spot/Non-Spot AP Constraint in Customer Tab in 1.4.1.6

--- Table 2 ---
Row 1: Department | Role/Contact | Email ID
Row 2: GHQ DYM BPM | Wan Yan Sia | wanyan.sia@one-line.com/ ghq.dym.bpm@one-line.com
Row 3: GHQ DYM BPM | Pamela Sevilla | pamela.sevilla@one-line.com/ ghq.dym.bpm@one-line.com

--- Table 3 ---
Row 1: Setup | Responsible party
Row 2: Master Constraint Table Creation | GHQ/RHQ Trade Teams
(Different setup can be done by Region)
Row 3: Standby Guidance Setup | GHQ/RHQ Trade Teams
(Different setup can be done by Region)
Row 4: Standby Priority Setup | GHQ/RHQ Trade Teams
(Different setup can be done by Region)
Row 5: Standby Role Setup | Regional BPIT

--- Table 4 ---
Row 1: Business Function Team | Business Role | OPUS SPC Tier | OPUS SPC Role | OPUS SPC Definition
Row 2: On/Off-Shore Booking Team | -Data entry
-Confirm booking if no constraints
Row 3: On/Off Shore CSVC Manager | -Data entry
-Confirm booking if no constraints | Tier 1 | BKG | On/Off Shore CSVC Manager
Row 4: On Shore CSVC Manager/ Approvers | -Confirm bookings escalated from Off-Shore Booking Staff | Tier 2 | BKG | On Shore CSVC Manager/ Approvers
Row 5: GHQ Space Control (Singapore, Hong Kong & Shanghai) | -Confirm bookings escalated from On shore Booking Office. | Tier 3 | SPC | GHQ/ RHQ space control, Marketing/ Equipment Manager in GHQ/ RHQ

--- Table 5 ---
Row 1: Guide Type | Final Guidance | Default BKG Status | Definition | Authorised party
Row 2: GD1 | OK to Book | W_F | Booking will be released by Off/ On Shore BKG staff after checking local constraints
Row 3: GD2 | Book to next available vessel | W_S | Booking will be 1) Standby,and escalate to On-shore or 2) Firm, and roll to the next available vessel
Row 4: GD3 | If necessary, escalate to CSVC manager (On/Off SHore) | W_S | Offshore BKG Staff can choose 1) Firm or 2) Escalate to the next level | Offshore BKG Staff
Row 5: GD4 | Escalate to CSVC manager | W_S | On/ Off shore CSVC Manager can 1) give direction to Offshore BKG Staff (Ok to book/ Cancel) 2) Escalate to the next level | On/ Off shore CSVC Manager
Row 6: GD5 | Escalate to RHQ and GHQ Space controllers | W_S | GHQ/ RHQ space controllers will give direction to On/ Off shore CSVC Manager (Ok to book/ Cancel) | GHQ/ RHQ Space controller
Row 7: GD6 | Decline | X | Booking will be cancelled automatically
Row 8: GDN (Special guidance in Priority Rule Setup) | Trunk-Loading/Customer is within allocation.

--- Table 6 ---
Row 1: Status | Definition
Row 2: F/ | Booking is firmed with no constraint
Row 3: F/F | Booking is firmed through Standby
Row 4: W/F | Booking Waiting/ Standby Approved
Row 5: W/S | Booking Waiting/ in Standby
Row 6: W/X | Booking Waiting/ Decline advised
Row 7: X/X | Booking is Cancelled due to Decline

--- Table 7 ---
Row 1: Constraint Type | Threshold % | Actual Booking | Guide | Guide (ETA-10)
Row 2: Trunk Overall | ABCD0001W | 100% | 98% | 4 | 4
Row 3: Trunk Loading | SHABB | 100% | 95% | 4 | 4
Row 4: Customer | XYZ00008A | 10 TEUs allocation | 9 TEUs | 4 | 4
Row 5: Final Guidance | Final Guidance | Final Guidance | Final Guidance | Final Guidance | GD1 | GD4

--- Table 8 ---
Row 1: Trunk Overall | To/From POR/POL/POD/DEL
Row 2: Allocation | 1000 | 300
Row 3: Total ONE Quote Bookings | 1020 | 200
Row 4: Standby guidance | GD6 | GD6 (as total trunk is full)

--- Table 9 ---
Row 1: Trunk Overall | To/From POR/POL/POD/DEL
Row 2: Allocation | 1000 | 300
Row 3: Total ONE Quote Bookings | 800 | 310
Row 4: Standby guidance | GD1 (exclude bookings exceeding POR/POL/POD/DEL) | GD6

--- Table 10 ---
Row 1: System Guidance | Current Process
Row 2: Customer Allocation | 10teus
Row 3: Current bookings | 7teus
Row 4: New booking | 5teus (Over by 2teus) | GD4- The whole lot will be escalated to Onshore | The whole lot will be pending
