=== PDF File: Shipping Industry - General Knowledge.pdf ===

Total Pages: 65

--- Page 1 ---
Shipping & Logistics 

--- Page 2 ---
Objectives: 
筐｢Know the Fundamentals of Shipping Industry 
筐｢Differentiate shipping from logistics and its importance. 
筐｢Be aware of how liner shipping works. 
筐｢Identify different types of cargo ship, container and cargo nature. 
筐｢Know the role and importance of Technology in Shipping and the terminologies 
used. 


--- Page 3 ---
Facts About Shipping 
笳週he international shipping industry is responsible for the carriage of around 90% 
of world trade. 
笳輯hipping is the life blood of the global economy. Without shipping, 
intercontinental trade, the bulk transport of raw materials, and the import/export 
of affordable food and manufactured goods would simply not be possible. 
笳輯hips are technically sophisticated, high value assets (larger hi-tech vessels can 
cost over US $200 million to build), and the operation of merchant ships 
generates an estimated annual income of over half a trillion US Dollars in freight 
rates. 
笳週here are around 50,000 merchant ships trading internationally, transporting 
every kind of cargo. 

--- Page 4 ---
Facts About Shipping 
笳輯hipping is the safest and most environmentally benign form of commercial 
transport. Perhaps uniquely amongst industries involving physical risk, 
commitment to safety has long pervaded virtually all deep sea shipping 
operations. 
笳終nherently international nature, the safety of shipping is regulated by various 
United Nations agencies (ie. IMO). 
笳輯hipping is the least environmentally damaging form of commercial transport 
and, compared with land based industry, is a comparatively minor contributor to 
marine pollution from human activities. 
笳週here has been a substantial reduction in marine pollution over the last 15 years, 
especially with regard to the amount of oil spilled into the sea, despite a massive 
increase in world sea borne trade. 


--- Page 5 ---
How Liner Shipping Works 
1.Liner ships offer regular scheduled services on 
fixed routes like a bus or train service does. 
2. Each shipment represent a specific supply chain. 
3.Every supply chain is unique 
          * involves the timely and accurate transfer of     
goods between various modes of transport.         
           * Goods transported by ocean containers on 
liner ships is placed in the container at 
                the factory origin. 
4.The container is locked and sealed so the goods 
can remain safely secured inside the container 
until it arrives at the purchaser窶冱 warehouse, 
factory or store. 


--- Page 6 ---
Importance of Shipping 
Importance of the role of shipping and ships can 
be appreciated from the fact that ships transport 
about 95% of world窶冱 cargo (including that by 
road, rail, air, and other means). The economy 
of the world depends upon shipping. All attempts 
are made to make ships suitable and 
economical for carrying different types of cargo. 


--- Page 7 ---
What is Shipping? 
Shipping is窶ｦ 
The act or business of transporting goods. The shipping  process follows the 
manufacture and the packing of goods and will be controlled by a shipping  or 
logistics company 


--- Page 8 ---
What is Logistics? 
Logistics means the movement of goods from one location to another . 
Common Modes of Transportation 


--- Page 9 ---
Transportation 
筐｢Transportation - The means of moving people and goods from origin to 
destination, inclusive of information interchange. 
筐｢窶廬ntermodal窶・Transportation - The concept of transporting passengers and/or 
freight from origin to destination in such a way that the parts of the 
transportation process, inclusive of information exchange are efficiently 
connected. 


--- Page 10 ---
Transportation 
Barge 
Railway Transportation 
Eco-Truck Intermodal Door-to-Door Transport 
笆ｪLess packaging material 
笆ｪLess labor input for packing and stowage 
work 
笆ｪLess transport damage 窶・lower 
insurance costs 
笆ｪLess storage space 窶・container as 窶徇ini 
warehouse 
Lower costs for customers 

--- Page 11 ---
Mode of Transportation 
Transportation Mode 
Description 
Motor Carrier 
Truckload, Less Than Truck Load 
Rail 
Railroad 
Small Package 
UPS, Federal Express, Airborne, etc.. 
Mail 
USPS 
Private Fleet 
Shipper's own vehicles 
Bulk 
Tank truck 
Ocean 
Ship, Barge, etc.. 
Other transportation modes : 

--- Page 12 ---
Types of Vessel 
There are two major categories (not counting the ships for defense 窶・Navy) - namely Cargo 
Ships and Passenger Ships. Cargo Ships are further subdivided into Dry Cargoes and Wet 
Cargoes as given in the chart below. There are other types that can be placed under 
窶・pecial category窶・ 
Cargo Ships  Passenger Ships 
Dry Cargo Ships Liquid Cargo Ships (Tankers) Cruise Liner 
General Cargo General Cargo 
(Boxes, Machinery, etc.) Oil Tankers Crude oil, refined oils, 
and petroleum products Ferries 
Container Vessel Containers Chemical Carriers Chemicals in bulk 
Bulk Carriers Bulk Cargos 
(Ore, Grain, Coal, 
Cﾃｩment, etc.) Gas Carriers Liquefied Gases 
(LNG, LPG, and other gases in 
liquid state) 
Roll On - Roll Off Vessel Trucks, trailers, vehicles 
Other ships:  Tug Boats, Offshore supply vessels, Cable laying ships, survey ships, Oil platforms, etc.. 

--- Page 13 ---
Types of Vessel 
General Cargo Ships: Are used for carrying 
different types of dry cargo in different sizes and 
shapes. This type is the earliest of cargo ships. 
First change was in the size of ships, then in 
method of packaging cargo, several other factors 
made the ships more and more specialized and 
thus different categories. 
A Container Ship  is one such advance version of 
general cargo ship providing options for different 
sizes of containers and a very speedy loading and 
discharging of cargo. 


--- Page 14 ---
Types of Vessel 
Bulk Carrier, bulk freighter, or bulker is a merchant 
ship used to transport unpackaged bulk cargo such as 
grain, coal, ore, cement and other similar cargoes. 
Roll-on/ Roll-off (RORO or ro-ro) is yet another 
version of a 窶賂eneral Cargo ship窶・designed to carry 
wheeled cargo such as automobiles, trailers or railroad 
cars. RORO vessels have built-in ramps which allow 
the cargo to be efficiently "rolled on" and "rolled off" the 
vessel when in port. Car/Truck Carriers are distinctive 
looking ships with a box-like superstructure running the 
entire length and breadth of the hull, fully enclosing and 
protecting the cargo. They typically have a stern ramp 
and a side ramp for dual loading of many thousands of 
vehicles, as well as extensive automatic fire control 
systems. 


--- Page 15 ---
Types of Vessel 
Passenger / Cruise Liners:  A passenger ship is a 
ship whose primary function is to carry passengers. 
The category does not include cargo vessels which 
have accommodations for limited numbers of 
passengers 
Tanker  is a ship designed to transport liquids in bulk. 
Petroleum tankers are a particular brand of tanker. A 
wide range of products are carried by tankers, 
including: 
窶｢Crude oil, refined oils, and many other liquids 
窶｢Chemical carrier is yet a specialized version of a 
tanker 
窶｢Yet another specialized version of a tanker is 
liquefied gas carriers - liquefied petroleum gas 
(LPG), liquefied natural gas (LNG), and other 
gases in liquid state 


--- Page 16 ---
Types of Vessel 
Tugboat, or tug,  is a boat, with a high-powered 
engine, used to maneuver, primarily by towing or 
pushing, other vessels in harbors, over the open sea 
or through rivers and canals. They are also used to 
tow barges, disabled ships, or other equipment like 
towboats. 
Offshore Supply Vessel (OSV):  OSV is a ship 
specially designed to supply offshore oil platforms. 
These ships range from 65 to 350 feet in length and 
accomplish a variety of tasks. The primary function 
for most of these vessels is transportation of goods 
and personnel to and from the offshore exploration 
activities. 


--- Page 17 ---
Types of Cargo & Its窶・Nature 

--- Page 18 ---
Container shipping company can provide service to inland location as well. 
Train &Truck & barge 
Ocean 
Where does shipping company offer service? 
Load Port/Discharge Port               = CY
Rail Ramp                                       = CY
Place of Receipt/Place of Delivery = CY or CFS or Door 

--- Page 19 ---
Example 1 
Cargo receipt at customer窶冱 warehouse.  Carrier appoints the trucker to pick up the 
laden container and then connect to appointed rail company under Carrier service.  
Rail 
Truck 
Ocean 
Myrtle, MS door - Memphis, TN 
Rail ramp 
Memphis, TN rail ramp 窶・
Los Angeles, CA 


--- Page 20 ---
Example 2 
Mother vessel Barge 
Truck 
Antwerp 
 窶・Brussels door 
Rotterdam 
  窶・Antwerp 
Discharge container at Rotterdam first and then connect to barge and truck.  
Carrier appoints barge company and truck company under Carrier service to 
customer. 

--- Page 21 ---
Types of Shipment 
笶詮CL(Full container Load) 
笶銑CL(Less than a container load) 
笶然oRo(Roll on 窶・Roll off) 
笶腺reak-bulk 


--- Page 22 ---
FCL and LCL 
 
FCL :               Full Container load. One container having cargo of only one  customer. 
LCL:                Less than container load. One container having cargoes of many customers. Full Container Load 
SealCargos 
Less than  Container  Load 
 Seal
CFS is used for LCL(Less than Container Load) cargos. 
Some customers don窶冲 have enough cargos to fill full container and shipping company receives LCL cargos at 
CFS and combines many LCL cargos to full 1 container. 
CFS Customer窶冱 warehouse / factory 
+ 
When shipper doesn窶冲 have enough cargo filled up a container, they don窶冲 have to pay for full container but pay for 
LCL only For FCL cargos, stuffing is under shipper窶冱 responsibility.  Shipper is responsible to arrange stuffing so that cargo 
can  endure various vibrations during transport. 

--- Page 23 ---
Nature of Cargo 
筐｢Temperature Control 
筐｢Dangerous Goods 
筐｢Out of Gauge Cargo-OOG 
筐｢Dry Cargo 


--- Page 24 ---
Containers 

--- Page 25 ---
Container Overview 
The container was invented by Malcolm P. McLean (trucker in the USA) in the 1930s 
窶｢ McLean wanted to improve the transport of goods by: 
  a. shortening of loading and discharge time 
b. making freight easily transferable from one mode 
     of transportation to another 
c. extend trucking aboard the ship 
d. It took 20 years from the idea to 1st deployment of  
                   a container: 
窶｢ April 1956 in Newark: First container loaded on a freight vessel 
窶｢ Today: Standard-format containers (20窶・40窶・ and a variety of 
   specialized containers (e.g. reefers) continuously increase 
   the share of containerized cargo 
窶｢ Container shipping is the backbone of globalization and 
  world trade and majority comply with the ISO standard. 


--- Page 26 ---
Advantages of a Container 
The standardization of the box resulted in continuous increase of the share 
of containerized freight: 
a. Intermodal door-to-door-transport 
b. Improved transit- and turnaround times 
c. Reduced handling costs 
d. Less damage of cargo 
e. Less Packing Material 
f.  Less Labor for Packing 
g. Less Storage 窶・Container as 窶哺ini-Warehouse 
筐｢Highly developed systems and measures of control are competitive 
success factors for liner shipping companies 


--- Page 27 ---
What is a Container? 
A container is a storage unit made up of steel. It is 
used for carrying goods from one place to another in a 
safe condition. 


--- Page 28 ---
Types of Containers 
Dry storage container  
The most commonly used shipping 
containers; they come in various dimensions 
standardized by ISO. They are used for 
shipping of dry materials and come in size of 
20ft/GP, 40 ft. GP/HC, 45HC, and 10ft. 
Flat rack container 
With collapsible sides, these are like simple 
storage shipping containers where the sides 
can be folded so as to make a flat rack for 
shipping of wide variety of goods. 


--- Page 29 ---
Types of Containers 
Refrigerated ISO containers or Reefer 
These are temperature regulated shipping 
containers that always have a carefully 
controlled low temperature. They are 
exclusively used for shipment of perishable 
substances like fruits and vegetables over 
long distances. 
Open top container 
With a convertible top that can be completely 
removed to make an open top so that 
materials of any height can be shipped easily. 


--- Page 30 ---
Types of Containers 
Tanks 
Container storage units used mostly for 
transportation of liquid materials, they are used 
by a huge proportion of entire shipping industry. 
They are mostly made of strong steel or other 
anti corrosive materials providing them with long 
life and protection to the materials. 


--- Page 31 ---
Different Sizes and Codes of Containers 
The following photo shows a variant of horizontal marking which additionally includes country, size and 
type codes (in accordance with the 1985 version of DIN ISO 6346, use of which is still permitted): 
Appropriate abbreviations are used for the various countries, here US for United 
States of America, GB for Great Britain etc. 
The first digit of the size code indicates the length of the container, with the 
number 4 standing for a 40' container. The second digit indicates height and 
whether or not a gooseneck tunnel is present. In our example, the number 3 
stands for a height of 8 foot 6 inches (8'6") with gooseneck tunnel. The first digit of 
the type code indicates container type. Here, 1 means that the container is a 
closed container with ventilation openings. The second digit of the type code 
relates to special features. The 0 used here means opening at the end. 

--- Page 32 ---
Different Sizes and Type Codes of Containers 
The standard establishes a visual identification system for every container  that includes a 
unique serial number  (with check digit), the owner, a country code, a size, type and equipment 
category as well as any operational marks. The standard is managed by the 
International Container  Bureau (BIC). Size and type codes additionally stated in accordance with current standard: 


--- Page 33 ---
Different Sizes and Type Codes of Containers 
TYPES OF CONTAINER MARKINGS 
Vertical marking 窶・the identifying details are 
more or less clearly visible 
Horizontal marking 
The owner code  and product group code  are also known as the alpha prefix. The check digit 
is often written in a box:  . 


--- Page 34 ---
笳輯hipper 
笳修onsignee 
笳洲reight Forwarder 
笳蒐VOCC 
笳修ustoms broker 
笳週erminal operator 
笳終ntermodal transport provider 
     (rail company/trucker/barge operator) 
笳舟aritime Authority 
  
Who is involved in container shipping transport? 

--- Page 35 ---
Business Negotiation & Finalization 
    Seller 
Buyer 
Consignee  : An individual or company to whom the goods are shipped.  Consignee is the customer at the destination who 
takes  ownership or  charge of the cargo from shipping line. Shipper :  Term used to describe exporter or seller. Shipper is the owner of the cargo. Shipper 
Exporter 
  Consignee 
Importer 
A Japanese bearing manufacturer supplies their 
products to the new plant. 
An automobile 
manufacturer launched new 
plant in USA. 
Goods 
筐｢Container shipping company works for sellers and their buyers all over the world. Shipper and Consignee 

--- Page 36 ---
Freight Forwarder 
笳洲reight Forwarder offers services of any kind relating to the container transport 
nevertheless domestic or international**.   Freight Forwarder is referred to Air 
freight forwarder and Sea freight forwarder. 
      ** consolidation, storage (warehouse), trucking, customs clearance, packing or 
distribution of the goods, collecting or producing payment or transport documents 
of the goods  etc... 
      
Pick & Pack 
Barcode   Label 
Services 
 Quality Assurance Shrink Wrap & 
Pallatization 
Tagging Garment On Hanger Sequential Loading 
Customs Management 


--- Page 37 ---
NVOCC 
笳蒐VOCC (Non-Vessel Operating Common Carrier) is a shipment 
consolidator or sea freight forwarder who does not own any vessel, but 
functions as a Transporter by assuming responsibility for the container 
shipments. 
      NVOCC acts 窶歪arrier to shipper窶・(from point of shipper) and 窶・hipper to 
carrier窶・(from point of carrier). 
 
Advantage of using NVOCC for shipper & consignee 
笳集hen shipper is unfamiliar to export procedure, they can rely on 
NVOCC窶冱 experience and knowledge. NVOCC has branches overseas. 
笳舟ore and more carriers stop providing CFS service.  When shipper doesn窶冲 
have enough cargo filled up a container, they use LCL service of NVOCC 
and the NVOCC sums up LCL cargos (from various customers) and make 
container full. Shipper only has to pay for LCL cargo volume instead of full 
container. 
     


--- Page 38 ---
Customs broker 
笳州efore the cargo leaves a country (for EXPORT) and the cargo enters into 
a country (for IMPORT), permission from a national customs authority 
needs to be granted.  A customs broker act on behalf of an exporter or 
importer and conduct documents arrangement and duties payment for 
permission. 
      Customs broker is one of Forwarder. 


--- Page 39 ---
Terminal operator 
笳週erminal operator checks container gate-in/gate-out at terminal and also 
makes container stacking planning at terminal and also loading/discharging 
planning at the port on behalf of the carrier. 
      Some terminal operators are a subsidiary or associated company of 
shipping carrier. 
Container Yard stacking planning 
       Vessel stowage planning at each loading port  

--- Page 40 ---
Maritime Authority 
笳週here are authorities regulating the waterborne foreign and domestic offshore 
commerce.  They ensure international trade is open to all nations on fair and 
equitable terms and protect against unauthorized activity. ONE has to comply 
with the regulations properly such as filing the rate and tariff in advance and 
checking valid license of NVOCC before signing up a contract. 
Example : 
1) FMC (Federal Maritime Commission) in the US 
2) China MOT (Ministry of Transport and Communications) 
In addition, complying Law and regulation related to transportation is important.   
e.g. IMDG code, Basel convention, SOLAS, Hague-Visby Rules, Anti Trust law  etc.. 


--- Page 41 ---
Documents and Services 

--- Page 42 ---
What is Bill of Lading (B/L)? 
Bill of Lading is a transport 
document issued or signed by 
a shipping carrier at the 
timing of receipt of cargo. 
B/L has 3 important 
characteristics. 


--- Page 43 ---
1) Evidence of the contract of carriage of goods 
         B/L is the evidence of the contract of carriage entered into between the 
窶徭hipping carrier窶・and 窶徭hipper or cargo owner窶・in order to carry out the 
transportation of the cargo as per the contract between the buyer and the 
seller. 
2) Proof of receipt for the goods shipped 
      B/L is issued by shipping carrier (or their agent) to the shipper in exchange 
for the receipt of the cargo. The issuance of B/L is proof that the carrier 
has received the goods from the shipper in apparent good order and 
condition, as handed over by the shipper. 
3) Document of Title 
     The holder of B/L is generally considered to be the owner of the cargo, and 
is entitled to delivery. 
3 important characteristics 

--- Page 44 ---
Sea Waybill 
笳輯ea Waybill 
B/L has the nature of 窶廛ocument of Title窶・  In case someone lost B/L, then there is potential risk that 
wrong party can receive the cargo.  In order to avoid the unnecessary risk, Sea Waybill is 
commonly used.    
Ocean B/L 
窶｢Evidence of the contract of carriage of 
goods 
窶｢Proof of receipt for the goods shipped 
窶｢Document of Title 
窶｢Negotiable Sea Waybill 
窶｢Evidence of the contract of carriage of 
goods 
窶｢Proof of receipt for the goods shipped 
窶｢Non Negotiable 
Mainly used for : 
New business, high-risk business Mainly used for : 
Parent company and subsidiary business 
Long-term partnership business 

--- Page 45 ---
Letter of credit 
笳・A letter of credit (L/C) is a written financial document issued by the consignee窶冱 (buyer窶冱) bank 
to guarantee the payment.  L/C is frequently used in container shipping transport.  
笳・L/C usually requires 窶廾n Board B/L窶・ 
Shipper(seller) Advising bank/ 
Confirming bank L/C Issuing bank 
Consignee(buyer) 
Shipping company 
(origin) Shipping company 
(destination) 1) Sales contract 2) L/C application 
request 3) L/C issue 
4) Advise L/C 
5) Goods 6) Issue B/L 7) B/L 
Commercial 
Invoice 8) Payment 9) B/L, Commercial Invoice 10) Payment 
11) Payment 
12) B/L 
14) Goods 13) B/L 

--- Page 46 ---
Who can hold Bill of Lading? 
Straight B/L 
      In straight B/L, consignee is already mentioned in B/L. 
      Delivery of cargo under a Straight B/L is generally to the named consignee only. 
     筐・Sea waybill is always Straight B/L and cannot be Order B/L. 
Order B/L 
In order B/L, consignee is not mentioned in B/L.   
      The indicated owner of the goods is transferred . When transferred the indicated 
owner of the goods, the person or company indicated is mentioned by endorsement. 
Delivery of cargo under an order B/L is generally made to the holder of the 
document. 


--- Page 47 ---
How is Bill of Lading created? 
Bill of Lading is created on basis of shipper窶冱 declaration.  We call this particular declaration form, 
窶彜hipping Instruction(S/I)窶・ 
Container is always gated in terminal with seal closure and shipping carrier cannot check container 
contents physically. 
In this regard, ONE always add 窶彜HIPPER窶儡 LOAD AND COUNT窶・窶彜AID TO CONTAIN窶・in 
additional to customer窶冱 declaration in order to prevent potential risks. 
筐尿ll B/L information becomes Manifest data which container shipping carrier is obligated to declare 
to customs on entry of the vessel and departure.  Fines are imposed if shipping carrier do not 
submit manifests to customs timely.  Manifests are transmitted to foreign ports to satisfy their 
own government customs requirements. 
筐祢n case there are Hazardous cargos contained, 
container shipping carrier needs to declare Manifest 
separately. 


--- Page 48 ---
When is Bill of Lading date? 
Shipped or On Board B/L  
B/L stating, 窶廰aden on Board窶・
The date when the goods are loaded to the vessel should be used as B/L date.  
Once shipping carrier confirms 窶彜hipped窶・& payment, B/L is issued.  
Received for Shipment B/L 
B/L stating, 窶彝eceived窶・
The date when the goods are gated-in should be used as B/L date. 
Although the intended vessel is named on B/L, there is no indication that the cargos have been loaded. 
B/L is issued after the date of receipt of the cargo & payment.  
IMPORTANT 
筐廼se of an earlier date would be considered a false entry.  
筐廼se of a later date, provided it is not later than the date of sailing,  is allowed under the Rules. B/L date is used in many ways.  The most common usage is 窶廾n Board Date窶・which states the 
goods are surely boarded onto the vessel (i.e. regarded as completion of export).  

--- Page 49 ---
Where is Bill of Lading issued & collected? 
笳・B/L issuance 
      Basically B/L is issued at the place of receipt office but also issued at an office other than the place 
of receipt office if customer requests.  
      In case the country is different between the issuing office and the place of receipt, this is called 
"third-country B/L issuance窶・   
笳・B/L collection 
      Basically B/L is collected at the place of destination office. 
笳・Surrendered B/L 
     Shipper can surrender B/L directly back to the office of the shipping company that issued them 
(usually after they confirm payment from consignee). This event eliminates the need for the 
consignee to provide an original B/L at destination and can speed up the release of cargos at 
destination.  Surrendered B/L is used especially in short distance shipment which cargo may 
arrive faster than B/L.   


--- Page 50 ---
House B/L 
笳終f B/L is issued by a shipping carrier to NVOCC, then another B/L which is 
called 窶・House  B/L窶・HBL) is issued by the NVOCC to their customers.  
Referring to this practice, B/I issued by a carrier is normally called 窶・Master 
B/L窶・MBL). 
笳終n the interest of the NVOCC and their insurance coverage/exposure, 
      all the details on HBL and MBL (e.g. vessel/voyage information, cargo 
description, number of containers, seal numbers, weight, measurements) 
usually remain the same. 
     The only difference should be the shipper and consignee details. 
In the HBL 
Shipper      : the actual shipper/exporter of the cargo 
Consignee : the actual receiver/importer of the cargo 
In the MBL 
Shipper      : the NVOCC, or their agent 
Consignee : the destination agent or counterpart of the NVOCC operator 


--- Page 51 ---
The flow of shipment 
Shipper Consignee 1) Business contract 
Tokyo 
Container terminal ONE Japan 
Container 
Depot 2) Booking 
3) Booking List 4) Empty 
container 
ONE5) Stuffing 
6) Laden 
container ONE
Los Angeles 
Container terminal ONE  America Tokyo 
Customs 7) Customs declaration (via Customs 
broker) 
8) Customs clearance 
9) S/I 
Offshore 10) B/L draft 11) Manifest (AMS) 
11) Confirmation 
12) Loading 14) Payment 15) B/L 
13) Loaded information US 
Customs 17) A/N 16) B/L 
24) Discharged information 19) Manifest 20) B/L 
        Payment 
21) Arrival 22) Discharging 23) D/O 
18) Manifest 25) Customs declaration 
26) Customs clearance 
ONE27) Laden container 28) Unstuffing 
29) Empty 
container 
Container 
Depot 

--- Page 52 ---
Ocean Freight inquiry 
Shipper Consignee 
Once the customer窶冱 business is finalized, either shipper or consignee contacts ONE local office and 
ask ocean freight.  (This can be before their business is finalized) 
ONE sales at local office is responsible to inform sailing schedule and quote ocean freight. 
Example 
Customer:    What is ONE schedule from Tokyo to Los Angeles, CA? 
ONE:            11 days transit time.  
                     Tokyo departure Saturday/ Los Angeles arrival Wednesday. 
Customer:     How much is the ocean freight? 
ONE:             USDXXXX/D2 subject to surcharges 
筐・Once the ocean freight is agreed, contract is signed up. 1) Business contract 

--- Page 53 ---
Shipper 
ONE Japan 2) Booking 
The things we need to know before taking a  
booking: 
窶｢Commodity 
窶｢Cargo Weight 
窶｢Type of container 
窶｢Date the customer wants to pick up the  container 
窶｢Location of container pick up and drop off 
窶｢Place of receipt / Place of delivery 
窶｢Port of loading / Port of discharge 
窶｢Contract number 
窶｢Customer contact info 窶廝ooking窶・is when shipper reserves 
space on a vessel as well as reserve a 
container for their cargo. 
Optional information 
窶｢Temperature settings (Reefer) 
窶｢Cargo size (Open top/Flat rack) 
窶｢Hazardous information (DG cargo) 
Booking  process 

--- Page 54 ---
We need to make sure vessel space and equipment are both available and customer窶冱 loading commodity 
is acceptable to on-board, and then release Booking number in exchange of 窶彗cceptance窶・ 
Booking number becomes reference number in the further communication. 
ONE services a variety of customers that making bookings in different ways: 
窶｢Email 
窶｢Phone 
窶｢EDI / Web 
(EDI = Electrical Data Interchange) 
Booking  process 
筐念nce the booking number is 
released, Booking data is 
created in OPUS system. 
Booking list is sent to terminal 
operator. 
(The list becomes available through 
OPUS system) 

--- Page 55 ---
Empty container pick up 
笳州efore shipper picks up empty container, they need to send pick up 
order (P/O) for smooth arrangement.  Terminal operator prepares 
container in accordance with P/O. 
笳州ooking number 
笳襲lace of receipt / Place of delivery 
笳襲ort of loading / Port of discharge 
笳襲ick up date 
笳襲ick up location 
笳修ontainer type / number 
笳修ustoms clearance status 
笳輯pecial request 
If reefer container窶ｦ 
笳週emperature 
笳襲re-cooling (needed / no need) 
笳酬entilation (open / close) 
Important 
Terminal operator checks if the contents 
match Booking data.  
If there is any discrepancy, terminal operator 
contact shipping carrier & shipper for 
clarification. 
Shipper 
Container 
Depot 4) Empty 
container ONE

--- Page 56 ---
Laden container gate-in 
笳週here is a certain time of period for container gate-in. 
CY OPEN 
Terminal capacity is limited.  In order to control terminal capacity and keep operational efficiency, 
CY Open is set up for each vessel. 
CY CUT 
In order to plan vessel stowage, CY CUT is set up for each vessel. 
CY Open 
Starting time of 
gate-in. 
CY CUT 
Deadline of 
gate-in. 
Vessel departure 
At the timing of gate-in, damage responsibility is under shipping carrier.  Terminal operator checks  
container has no damage before gate-in and then release Equipment Interchange Receipt (EIR) as  
an evidence of container receipt.   If shipper doesn窶冲 bring laden container before CY 
CUT, it窶冱 not possible to load onto scheduled vessel. 


--- Page 57 ---
B/L creation 
笳州/L is created at either onshore or offshore based on S/I submitted by 
customer. 
笳輯/I(Shipping Instruction) contains : 


--- Page 58 ---
AMS filing / ENS filing 
笳・AMS (Automated Manifest Service) is advance notification of shipments to U.S. Customs and 
Border Protection.  The authority can reject any suspicious cargos at origin before the goods 
physically reach US shores.  AMS filing needs to be made in 24 hours prior to the onset of 
loading. 
笳・Similar to AMS Filing, ENS (Entry Summary Declaration) is submitted electronically by 
shipping carriers for all members of the European Union.  This too means the EU has prior 
notification of cargos being imported into their regions and can be rejected if deemed of a 
suspicious nature, as with the US, ENS filing needs to be made in 24 hours prior to the onset of 
loading. 
     Other 24-Hours Advance Manifest filing rules : 
     Canada(ACI), Mexico(AMS), Japan(AFR), China(CCAM) 
  


--- Page 59 ---
Confirmation / Loaded information 
笳週erminal operator summarizes all containers intended to load onto the 
vessel and cross-checks with carrier窶冱 booking list if there is any 
discrepancy.  They also confirm if all containers cleared customs.  Once it窶冱 
confirmed, terminal operator arranges customs clearance of containers 
themselves* and proceeds loading containers onto the vessel and reports to 
customs after its completion. 
   * Customs clearance for container itself 
      Apart from cargos, container itself needs to be customs-cleared.  This is not 
under shipper窶冱 responsibility but under carrier窶冱 responsibility because the 
containers are owned by carrier.  
    
  


--- Page 60 ---
A/N (Arrival Notice) 
笳愁estination local office sends Arrival Notice(A/N) either by fax or email to 
customer so that consignee can prepare cargo receipt. 
      This arrival notice includes function of invoice.   
      (Format is basically same as B/L) 
      Important remark: 
      A/N is not the obligation task to ONE.  This is one of ONE窶冱 customer 
service and customer should be responsible for contacting carrier and 
check the arrival information of their cargo. 


--- Page 61 ---
Manifest 
笳・Manifest data is sent to Customs usually through EDI.     
      Manifest data is also sent out to terminal operator before vessel窶冱 arrival as well as other 
information such as special cargos(Reefer cargos, DG, OOG), Animal Quarantine/ Plant 
Quarantine list* and Bay plan. 
 
Plant-related: 
Fresh, cut or dried flowers, leaves, roots, bark or other plant 
products (could include potpourri, garlands, wreaths, baskets 
made of plant material, etc.) 
Tobacco (excludes rolled cigarettes or cigars), tobacco leaves 
Fresh or frozen fruit or vegetables 
Non-roasted coffee beans 
Beans, except canned-beans 
Soil 
Wheat, sesame, cotton, grain, barley, malt, straw, rice, flour, 
herbs, spices, tea (tea bags accepted), mushrooms, sugar cane 
Wood, nursery tree, bulbs Animal-related:  
Meat, frozen meat, meat products, ham, 
sausage, beef jerky, including canned, bottled 
and vacuum-pouched products 
Bacteria, viruses (human or animal) 
Animal origin blood, blood product, serum, 
antibody, semen, tissue 
Animal bone, horn, antler 
Unprocessed animal fur, feathers 
Gelatin, collagen 
Pet food, wood or chews 
Raw wool or leather 
Insects *Items which my require 窶廣nimal Quarantine窶・or 窶弃lant Quarantine窶・include the following 
types of products: 

--- Page 62 ---
D/O(Delivery Order) release 
1)   Consignee approaches ONE office at the place of destination and submit 
endorsed original B/L and pay destination charges. 
2)   ONE released Delivery Order(D/O) after confirming payment and 
endorsed original B/L. 
3)   Consignee submits D/O to terminal operator and pick up laden containers 
from terminal. 
     Important remark: 
      Nowadays, Paper Delivery Order is no longer used and Electrical Delivery 
Order (through EDI system) is replaced in many countries. 

--- Page 63 ---
Discharged information & customs clearance 
笳・Terminal operator declares to customs that the containers were discharged at the terminal, 
together with the containers themselves for customs clearance.  Once consignee declares and 
clears customs for their cargos, carrier can release imported containers to consignee.  
笳・When consignee declares to customs, they need to submit related import documents and pay the 
duties to customs before clearance. 
笳・In case physical exam (including Animal Quarantine/ Plant Quarantine) or X-Ray exam is 
required by customs, it is carried at container terminal or customs exam site and then customs 
gives permission to consignee. 
  


--- Page 64 ---
Laden gate-out 
笳州efore consignee picks up laden container, they need to send request form 
to terminal in advance.   
笳就fter the timing of gate-out, damage responsibility is under consignee.  
Terminal operator checks container has no damage before gate-out and 
then release Equipment Interchange Receipt (EIR) as an evidence of 
container release.  
笳修onsignee de-stuffs the laden container and return the empty container 
back to the container depot. 


--- Page 65 ---
Demurrage & Detention 
笳・Storage fee (Demurrage) 
      All ports and rail ramp have unique free time period and cost calculation.  Normally there is 2-5 
calendar days free-time commencing from discharge of container and consignee is required to 
pick up laden containers within the free-time. If they exceeds the free-time, storage fee is applied.  
笳・Equipment rental fee (Detention) 
     Each carrier sets free-time period for improving the turn round time of containers.   Normally, 
free-time allows 3-7 calendar days.  After the expiry of free-time, detention equipment rental fee 
is applied. 
Important remark: 
  The usage of Demurrage and Detention differs in each country. 
   In some countries, equipment rental fee incurs while the container is even situated at the 
  container yard.    
  In some countries, demurrage means equipment rental fee and detention means demurrage.  
  When you communicate, better to use 窶彜torage窶・and 窶廢quipment rental窶・for safety sake.   
